Utkarsh Chawla

Bengaluru, Karnataka • +91-8881718354 • utkarshchawla4@gmail.com • Linkedin

Business Operations Associate

Experienced professional with two-plus years in Business Operations, Project Management, and Business Analysis. Skilled in MS Excel, BigQuery, and MySQL, excelling in client-business team communication. Customer-centric, aligning product/engineering teams for enhanced accessibility and bug resolution via Zendesk. Proven collaboration with design teams, creating marketing collateral.

Experience

Business Operations Associate, Good Business Lab

March 2023 - Present, Bengaluru

- Worked on analyzing data of Inache, a two-way anonymous communication tool for factory workers.
- Monitored and evaluated processes using SQL and Excel to find areas of improvement, significantly improving the client experience by 50% by advising resource allocation to user role-specific training.
- Helped **improve product accessibility** with timely resolution of bugs and cross-team vendor/stakeholder management through Zendesk.
- Conducted 10-plus user interactions across different units to help align product/engineering teams to a **customer-centric vision** for the product.
- Completed analysis of anonymous survey data based on age, gender, and experience for the **2000** sample size of factory workers.
- Coordinated with the design team to create the marketing **collaterals** for product launch.
- Conducted testing for version 2 and synced with the engineering

Junior Analyst, GfK

December 2021 - March 2023, Gurugram

- Exceeded monthly KPIs for six months in a row.
- Identifying key insights and **trends in data** that inform business decisions.
- Communicating with International Clients to fulfill their requirements and ensuring the completion of Projects.

September 2021 – December 2021, Delhi

- Identifying and implementing **process improvements** to increase efficiency and productivity.
- Completing projects within scope and on time.
- Ensuring to surpass all performance and quality goals.

Customer Care Executive, Vamaship

November 2020 - February 2021, Mumbai

- Handling Customer queries through calls and chat
- Offered strong customer service skills, keeping customers satisfied and increasing customer satisfaction ratings by an average of 20% monthly.

Education

Graduated 08/2021

Bachelors in Business Administration, PSIT - Kanpur

Skills

Business Operations, Excel/Google Sheets Powerpoint, Canva, Problem Solving, Agile, Project Implementation, SQL, Business Analysis, Power BI, client relations, Vendor Management, BigQuery, MySQL

Certificates

<u>HackerRank Basic SQL certificate</u> <u>HackerRank Intermediate SQL certificate</u>